<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peated Whiskies on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bottletags/peated-whiskies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peated Whiskies on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bottletags/peated-whiskies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ardbeg Uigeadail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ardbeg-uigeadail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ardbeg-uigeadail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ardbeg Uigeadail combines the typical Ardbeg flavors, smokiness and salty notes, with chocolaty sweetness and raisin flavors. fit Montecristo cigars to this whiskey. Named after the Uigeadail source from which the Ardbeg distillery produces its peaty water, the Ardbeg Uigeadail sets new standards in matters of complexity and harmony. The 10-year marriage bourbon barrels with older sherry casks gives an abundance of flavors, which in addition magnificently describe the Ardbeg Uigeadail. The connection Islay &amp;amp; Ardbeg typical aromas with flavors of sherry casks is unique. The Ardbeg Islay Uigeadail is a single malt whiskey, which is produced in the region of Scotland Islay. the clear waters of Ardbeg, which gives a pleasant peaty taste the whiskey is used. The maturation takes place in bourbon and sherry casks, which is noticeable in the aroma. This looks smoky, intense smells of leather, tobacco and a slight fruitiness. Also on the palate also one perceives smokiness, a light malt flavor, licorice and a hint of citrus. Overall, a balanced, lush taste. In conclusion, the connoisseurs of a long-lasting taste pleased paired with a fine sherry. An aromatic wine for connoisseurs and novices alike. The Ardbeg Islay Whiskey Uigeadail should be in every bar. The best It tasted straight or with some ice. Ardbeg Uigeadail is a 70 year old single malt whisky from the Ardbeg whisky distillery (located in the Islay region). Rated an average of 4.6 out of 5 by 797 reviewers and available from Master of Malt for only £52.95, falling slightly short of liquid gold but this in a solid everyday single malt whisky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cardhu Gold Reserve Cask Selection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cardhu-gold-reserve-cask-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cardhu-gold-reserve-cask-selection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cardhu Gold Reserve Cask Selection is a single malt whisky from the Cardhu whisky distillery (located in the Speyside region). Rated an average of 4.7 out of 5 by 282 reviewers and available from Amazon for only £34.95, falling slightly short of liquid gold but this in a solid everyday single malt whisky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glengoyne 21 Year Old Sherry Cask</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/glengoyne-21-year-old-sherry-cask/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/glengoyne-21-year-old-sherry-cask/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For twenty-one years, the Glengoyne 21 Years matures in First Fill sherry casks from European oak. In it It develops a deep and complex taste that lives entirely on the oak wood note and the expressive sherry aromas. Glengoyne has made a real coup with this single Highland Malt. If you let your nose float over the edge of the glass, you will hear a smell of red apples, vanilla pods, honey, pastries and fresh hay. On the tongue, the oak wood aroma then smacks like a bomb, sending waves after wave of warm spiciness across all taste buds. When the smoke clears, the charming scotch leaves with a ginger-colored adíos that makes you grateful for the beautiful finish in Spanish wood.90 / 100 points. Jim Murray’s Whiskey Bible 2010. The Glengoyne 21 Years is in the truest sense of the word a golden boy. The Single Highland Malt has received the highest honors from international critics and been awarded gold medals for its exquisite taste. Glengoyne 21 Year Old Sherry Cask is a 21 year old single malt whisky from the Glengoyne whisky distillery (located in the Highland region). Rated an average of 4.6 out of 5 by 137 reviewers and available from Amazon for only £125.0, falling slightly short of liquid gold but this in a solid everyday single malt whisky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
