<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whiskies of Ireland on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bottletags/whiskies-of-ireland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whiskies of Ireland on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bottletags/whiskies-of-ireland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hinch 10 Year Old Sherry Cask Finished Irish Whiskey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hinch-10-year-old-sherry-cask-finished-irish-whiskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hinch-10-year-old-sherry-cask-finished-irish-whiskey/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redbreast 12 Year Old Cask Strength Batch B1-18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/redbreast-12-year-old-cask-strength-batch-b1-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/redbreast-12-year-old-cask-strength-batch-b1-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tullamore Dew Blended Irish Whiskey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tullamore-dew-blended-irish-whiskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tullamore-dew-blended-irish-whiskey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Tullamore Dew from the south of Ireland is a rich blend whose fine smoky taste of honey gives it an unforgettable aromatic expression. It can be compared to another Irish whiskey barely. Golden yellow barley and clear spring water form the basis of Tullamore Dew. The distillery Tullamore, which is now owned by Allied Domecq, was founded in 1829 in the county Offlay and later taken over by Daniel E. Williams, who helped the contemporary blend to its name. The The Tullamore Dew is an established Irish whiskey. It was first produced in 1829, founded by Michael Molloy Tullamore distillery in the same place Irish Tullamore in County Offaly. The suffix Dew goes back to Daniel Edmond Williams, the 1887 was chief executive of the distillery of the year and his initials D.E.W. anhängte the name of the whiskey. Today Tullamore Dew is part of the Scottish company William Grant &amp;amp; Sons and is produced in Midleton. The Tullamore Dew is a blended whiskey, which is a compilation of different single whiskeys. It tastes mild compared to other whiskeys and has not too strong and dominant flavors. It has, in comparison to most whiskeys, no smoky flavor, which makes it taste more pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redbreast 12 Year Old Single Pot Still Irish Whiskey 70cl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/redbreast-12-year-old-single-pot-still-irish-whiskey-70cl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 13:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/redbreast-12-year-old-single-pot-still-irish-whiskey-70cl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among connoisseurs of Redbreast 12 Years among the best what of whiskies to offer Ireland. The phases of maturity in bourbon and Oloroso cask give the Redbreast 12 Years unbeatable and rare taste. 1939 Redbreast is the first time in the trade. it was produced at that time in the Jameson distillery, stored, packaged and sold it the company has Gilbey. After the Jameson distillery was closed, one has the pure pot still delivered only to mid 80s. A few years ago the brand was revived thanks to the IDG and manufactured in New Midleton today. Earlier the Redbreast had an excellent reputation and is considered one of the last Irish whiskey of its kind. The Redbreast 12 Years is a world class pure pot still whiskey. The bottle is also called &amp;ldquo;The Priest Bottle&amp;rdquo; because the Irish pot still to have earlier pampers the palate of priests. The Redbreast is a traditional Irish whiskey, which is produced in the pot still procedure. This means that the distillation is carried out in stills of copper. Because after each operation, the bubbles must be cleaned carefully, the Redbreast is not suitable for mass production. Furthermore, the addition of water is omitted before bottling. The concentration is the same as that in the storage barrels. Of course, the alcohol content of the whiskey is high and only for hard-drinking connoisseurs. The aroma of Redbreast is fruity with hints of malt and sherry. The latter comes from the storage casks. The taste is very diverse, with hints of sherry, spices, vanilla and oak. A total of more powerful and complex taste. The finish also not disappointed: very long lasting, intense with hints of dark berry fruits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
