<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Best Blended Malt Whiskies for Under £50 on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bottletags/best-blended-malt-whiskies-for-under-50/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Best Blended Malt Whiskies for Under £50 on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bottletags/best-blended-malt-whiskies-for-under-50/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roughstock Montana Pure Malt Whiskey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/roughstock-montana-pure-malt-whiskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/roughstock-montana-pure-malt-whiskey/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Peat Islay Blended Malt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/big-peat-islay-blended-malt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/big-peat-islay-blended-malt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Big Peat convinces with its strong smoky and phenolic character that will convince especially lovers of Islay whiskeys. According to the manufacturer of the Big Peat should represent the ultimate taste of Islay. A Hidden Malt, which reflects the taste of Islay - the Big Peat. known in normal filling, but now available in a miniature, it is referred to by experts as the ultimate Islay whiskey. Five distilleries are in the process involved in creating this unique blend. Four of them deliver their varieties Port Ellen, Ardbeg, Bowmore and coal Ila. The fifth part in the processing and fills from. The result is a joint project of the islanders, which now is very popular among friends of the original and peaty whiskeys. Both smell and taste live mainly of smoke and peat, but replaced by a discreet sweetness. In addition, the connoisseurs will recognize the aroma of beach and tar, smoke and peat. The finish of the taste of liquorice and fire support the main flavor. Friends speak of understated nut character, baked almonds and salted cashews to which this whiskey recalls. In addition, a touch of cocoa beans and sandalwood - It is also quite dry. A coveted award was the Big Peat given in 13: It was winner of the title &amp;ldquo;Best Blended Scotch Malt Whiskey&amp;rdquo; at the World Awards. This maybe also contributed to the unusual label, reminiscent of a comic book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compass Box The Spice Tree Highland Blended Malt Scotch Whisky</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/compass-box-the-spice-tree-highland-blended-malt-scotch-whisky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 13:31:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/compass-box-the-spice-tree-highland-blended-malt-scotch-whisky/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
