<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vintage 2002 - Whiskies Made in 2002 on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bottletags/vintage-2002---whiskies-made-in-2002/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vintage 2002 - Whiskies Made in 2002 on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bottletags/vintage-2002---whiskies-made-in-2002/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dalwhinnie 2002 Distillers Edition /2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dalwhinnie-2002-distillers-edition-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dalwhinnie-2002-distillers-edition-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spicy, peaty malt and sherry sweetness with a dry Abgang.Die Distillers Edition Dalwhinnie is a special bottling of Scottish distillery. The malt distillery Dalwhinnie is the highest elevation in Scotland and is located in the Central Highlands. The batch is abgefülllt once a year, individually numbered and individually marked. The Dalwhinnie Distillers Edition undergoes a second maturation phase in Oloroso oak barrels. It smells of grapes and has been carefully chosen to complement the characteristic, peat, peat and heather honey notes of Dalwhinnie. It is characterized by a strong vinous sweet, spicy complexity and a very dry, oak accented finish. Region: Highland Color: succinic nose: Fresh Sherry complements the malzigeren, honey-like sounds of Dalwhinnie. Peaty and surprising, but still pagan emphasized. Spicy but vinous body also: Mild to moderate palate: Spicy tingling, followed by the impressive building a very clear and well-structured malts. After a quick burst of sweetness a rich appeal of grapes departure comes: Much, much oak. Very, very dry with dominant vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
