<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:35:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is The Angels Share?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/what-is-the-angels-share/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:35:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/what-is-the-angels-share/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-angels-share&#34;&gt;What Is The Angels Share?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Angels Share is alcohol lost due to evaporation during the maturation of whisky. The exact amount lost to evaporation varies based on the properties of the wood, the skill of the cooper, the humidity of the region and how regularly the casks are turned. The term is also the name of a Scottish comedy drama directed by Ken Loach centered around a fictional cask of Islay’s Malt Mill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distilling The myth of Canadian Whisky</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/distilling-myth-canadian-whisky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 12:47:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/distilling-myth-canadian-whisky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Canadian whisky sometimes suffers from a whirlwind of contrary media, some going so far as to call it brown vodka, some calling it the best whisky in the world and others highlighting the 9.09% rule.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Points of interest on Canadian whisky:&#xA;The terms &amp;ldquo;Canadian Whisky&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Rye Whisky&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Canadian Rye Whisky&amp;rdquo; are legally indistinguishable in Canada and do not require any specific grain in their production and are often blends of two or more grains&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jim Murray did award Crown Royal Northern Harvest Rye “World Whisky of the Year 2016”&#xA;Canadian whisky can indeed contain 9.09% non-whisky alcohol&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They don’t export too much of it outwith the Americas (until very recently Canadian whisky was the most popular whisky in America)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;canadas-world-whisky-of-the-year-award&#34;&gt;Canada’s World Whisky of the Year Award&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with Jim Murray and his award (One man’s opinion). Yes it won the award (again one man’s often questionable/bias opinion). Apart from talking a lot of guff on a variety of topics being controversial is how he gets headlines, which is how he makes money by selling books, running tastings etc. Put simply if Jim Murray consistently awarded Scottish whiskies this award would anyone really care outwith the usual whisky pundits. None of which is to say that he’s wrong (though i certainly know no-one who shares this opinion) - this kind of headline does bother me though (If i’m being honest this fills me with a barely contained fury that suggests I may have deeper issues for which I may need counselling).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Still Vs. Pot Still</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/continuous-still-vs-pot-still/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 21:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/continuous-still-vs-pot-still/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The difference of flavour between Malt and Blend whiskies can &lt;em&gt;largely&lt;/em&gt; be traced to three factors, the grain used, the way it&amp;rsquo;s distilled, and the way the alcohol is matured. While the influence of the later is cited as high as 70% (by the Scottish Whisky Association) or around 50% by US Bourbon makers the type of still used has historically, and every distillery places emphasis on the quality of its grain the type of still has arguably changed the global face of whisky more than either. Ironic for a country associated with malt whisky production it was among other political considerations, the early adoption of the continuous still over the pot still, which put Scotch to the forefront of whisky making at the expense of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The £1 million Rose of Annandale</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/annandale-distillery-first-cask/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 19:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/annandale-distillery-first-cask/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Annandale distillery re-opened in 2007 has become the first Scotch to put its first cask up for sale, for the eye-watering price of £1 million. In a stroke of marketing genius that will certainly make the world take notice. The restored and refurbished whisky distillery and visitor centre sees the water of life return to Dumfries-shire a long term dream of Professor David Thompson 59 his wife Teresa Church 55. Production began in 2014 and the first fill is expected to be matured for at least 10 years, though it could legally be opened in 2018 after maturing for its &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uiscebeatha.co.uk/bourbon-vs-whisky/&#34;&gt;minimum of 3 years&lt;/a&gt; and still be considered a Scotch&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barley &amp; The James Hutton Institute</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/barley-james-hutton-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 08:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/barley-james-hutton-institute/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from the publishing of a high resolution draft of the barley genome in the journal Nature the James Hutton Institute is hoping to establish a £23m international centre for the study of barley, with the hopes of creating hardier, more resistant strains for use the production of biofuel, beer and of course whisky. Barley is already the second most important crop in UK agriculture, grown across almost 50% of Scotland&amp;rsquo;s arable land and underpinning the Scotch whisky industry &lt;a href=&#34;http://uiscebeatha.co.uk/scotch-whisky-industry-turmoil/&#34;&gt;£5 billion&lt;/a&gt; per year contribution to the UK economy, so this development is likely to receive considerable support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
