<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lowland Whiskies on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bottletags/lowland-whiskies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lowland Whiskies on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bottletags/lowland-whiskies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Glenkinchie 2005 Distillers Edition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/glenkinchie-2005-distillers-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/glenkinchie-2005-distillers-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An impressive malt whiskey; fascinating and pleasant temperature whiskey distillery Glenkinchie is often referred to as &amp;ldquo;The Edinburgh Malt&amp;rdquo; because the distillery is located in the immediate vicinity of the city. a batch of Distillers Edition is brought out once a year, the individually numbered, and each bottle is identified. The limited edition of this single malt Scotch whiskey undergoes the second meiotic phase Amontillado wooden barrel. It was selected because of its nutty flavor to round out the sweet and dry character of the Glenkinchie elegant and deepen. On the palate, firm, dry and very malty with a spicy, eichenholzbetontem finish. Region: LowlandsFarbe: Auburn nose: Forsch, sharp and brittle, and exceptionally complex; amazing balance between sweet and dry. Firmer, drier notes of soft vanilla to fresh grapes. Sweeter, nussigere tones come from the malted barley and the barrel wood. Body: Solid, mild to moderate palate: dry, after previous Cookie sweetness. Great malt character contrasts with the fruity-ness of the grape Finish: Very long, dry, oak emphasized. Very little peppery notes add spice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auchentoshan 21 Year Old</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/auchentoshan-21-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/auchentoshan-21-year-old/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Auchentoshan 21 Years is a complex, yet mild Scotch whisky. Its fresh, floral fragrance leaves you wanting more, and in the taste of the Auchentoshan delivers what it promises. The Auchentoshan 21 Years is of course three times distilled, and was over 20 years aged in American bourbon barrels and Spanish sherry casks. The long storage time in different barrels have made a kompklexen yet mild Auchentoshan arise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auchentoshan Virgin Oak Batch Two</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/auchentoshan-virgin-oak-batch-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/auchentoshan-virgin-oak-batch-two/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamiltons Lowland Single Grain Whisky</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hamiltons-lowland-single-grain-whisky/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hamiltons-lowland-single-grain-whisky/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
