<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Best Single Malt Whiskies for Under £50 on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bottletags/best-single-malt-whiskies-for-under-50/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Best Single Malt Whiskies for Under £50 on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bottletags/best-single-malt-whiskies-for-under-50/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cardhu Gold Reserve Cask Selection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cardhu-gold-reserve-cask-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cardhu-gold-reserve-cask-selection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cardhu Gold Reserve Cask Selection is a single malt whisky&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Penderyn Independence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/penderyn-independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/penderyn-independence/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talisker 10 Year Old</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/talisker-10-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/talisker-10-year-old/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Talisker 10 Years is strong in flavor, peppery and marked by maritime flavors. The Talisker 10 Years is delivered in a gift box! The Talisker 10 comes from the single distillery of the Isle of Skye. The whiskeys of the distillery are among the most popular spirits in the world. To date, one of the pfeffrigsten Single Malts is baked in the world in the distillery. Smoky, malty-sweet, with very strong pepper. For several years It has been a fixed feature of the Classic Malts Selection. This has made it even more popular, despite or because of the very strong flavors. At least once you should have the Talisker 10 Years tried. Talisker 10 Years is a 10 year old Scottish single malt Scotch whiskey. It is produced by the Talisker Distillery, the only distillery on the Isle of Skye in Scotland. The Talisker 10 Years tastes sweet dried fruit, but also has a smoky and peppery note. Especially in the finish It is very strong, here are the peppery comes into its own. Its aroma is also characterized by strong peat smoke, which is in contrast to the fruity sweetness and so shapes the unique taste of Talisker whiskey, making it thus one of the most powerful in taste malts, which are currently producing. Clearly visible is the Talisker 10 Years on his golden brown, rich color.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classic Malts Strong Collection 3x20cl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classic-malts-strong-collection-3x20cl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classic-malts-strong-collection-3x20cl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1770 Whisky - 2019 Release</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/1770-whisky-2019-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/1770-whisky-2019-release/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highland Park 12 Year Old 2 Glass Pack Island Whisky</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/highland-park-12-year-old-2-glass-pack-island-whisky/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/highland-park-12-year-old-2-glass-pack-island-whisky/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glenglassaugh Port Wood Finish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/glenglassaugh-port-wood-finish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/glenglassaugh-port-wood-finish/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lagavulin 16 Year Old 70cl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lagavulin-16-year-old-70cl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lagavulin-16-year-old-70cl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Lagavulin 16 Years is the best-selling member of the Classic Malts of Scotland. A powerful, smoky and complex Islay Malt. A true classic! The distillery Lagavulin on Islay is renowned for its peaty whiskeys. It is located in close proximity to the distilleries of Ardbeg and Laphroaig. This also applies to the Lagavulin 16 Years. Although the finish and sherry casks (Sherry Cask) were used remains that there are strong, smoky. Beginners should not start with this whiskey. The Lagavulin 16 Years is a whiskey for connoisseurs and lovers of Islay whiskeys. The Lavagulin 16 Years Old Islay Malt is said to have an absolutely unmistakable and strong character. It has an unrivaled composition of earth, sea, peat and smoke. When speaking of the spiciest Islay Malt, as connoisseurs know that here the Lavagulin 16 Years Old is meant. Especially popular is the 43% vol. alcoholic Lavagulin due to its deep taste and its noble drought. The 16-year-old whiskey is the most popular and best selling Classic Malt series. The flavor notes of Lavagulin 16 Years Old Islay Malt consist of fruity cherry, delicate vanilla and other various spices. More information about the product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glenmorangie Quinta Ruban 14 Year Old Port Finish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/glenmorangie-quinta-ruban-14-year-old-port-finish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 14:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/glenmorangie-quinta-ruban-14-year-old-port-finish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Glenmorangie Quinta Ruban 14 years is produced in the Scottish distillery Glenmorangie, which is renowned for its quality whiskey. Already in the early 18th century whiskey was distilled here. The suffix &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; Quinta &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; refers to the Portuguese wine barrels in which the whiskey matures. The Gaelic word &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; Ruban &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; stands for Rubin and describes the color of Glenmorangie, which is actually ruby ​​red with a brownish tinge. When serving the Glenmorangie exudes a complex aroma that consists of mint, chocolate and tangerines. The taste is initially spicy, then chocolaty-nutty. The whole is pervaded by a subtle hint of mint and lemon. A total refreshing, spicy yet smooth whiskey, which also ensures a long, pleasant finish. It should enjoy pure necessarily alternatively with some ice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suntory Yamazaki Distiller&amp;#039;s Reserve Japanese</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/suntory-yamazaki-distillers-reserve-japanese/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/suntory-yamazaki-distillers-reserve-japanese/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cotswolds Single Malt 2014 Odyssey Barley English</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cotswolds-single-malt-2014-odyssey-barley-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 13:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cotswolds-single-malt-2014-odyssey-barley-english/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
