<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whiskies of America on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bottletags/whiskies-of-america/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whiskies of America on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bottletags/whiskies-of-america/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jack Daniels Master Distiller No 5 Tennessee Whiskey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jack-daniels-master-distiller-no-5-tennessee-whiskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jack-daniels-master-distiller-no-5-tennessee-whiskey/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jim Beam Devil&amp;#039;s Cut Bourbon Kentucky Straight Bourbon Whiskey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jim-beam-devils-cut-bourbon-kentucky-straight-bourbon-whiskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jim-beam-devils-cut-bourbon-kentucky-straight-bourbon-whiskey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The counterpart to the &amp;ldquo;Angel&amp;rsquo;s Share&amp;rdquo; (the liquid that &amp;ldquo;evaporated&amp;rdquo; during the Whiskey storage in the drums) is the &amp;ldquo;Devil&amp;rsquo;s Cut&amp;rdquo; (the amount of whiskey, which remains in the timber after the whiskey maturation and emptying of the flamed oak barrels). Thanks to a patented method, which can extract &amp;ldquo;Devil&amp;rsquo;s Cut&amp;rdquo; from the barrels and combine with a minimum of six-year-old Jim Beam. The result is an intense, strong Bourbon, which provides an incomparable taste experience, the Jim Beam Devil&amp;rsquo;s Cut. Jim Beam Bourbon is the best selling brand in the world - Its origins date back to the 18th century, when the German-born Müller Jakob Bohm came with his copper pot stills of Virginia westward to Bourbon Country (Kentucky). It is said to have 1,795 sold his first barrel of whiskey in cash and eventually moved his distillery to Washington County. Jim (James Beauregard) Beam was Jacob Boehm&amp;rsquo;s great-grandson. It joined the family business at the age of 16 years. The Jim Beam Devils Cut whiskey is produced in Clermont, in the US state of Kentucky. The well-known distillery has been producing since 1795. whiskey. The Jim Beam Devils Cut is a new creation. When storing two &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; Outtakes &amp;lsquo;distinguish&amp;rsquo;. The &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; angel&amp;rsquo;s cut &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; is the portion that evaporates during maturation by the barrel pores, the &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; devil&amp;rsquo;s cut &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; is the residue that remains after emptying of the barrels. This relatively small amount, the &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; Devil&amp;rsquo;s share &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, is married with six year old Jim Beam whiskey and produces a particularly rich, intense whiskey with an equally strong coloration. The bouquet is smoky oak flavors and delicate vanilla unfold. On the palate, the new creation convinces with an intense vanilla and cinnamon note, wood and caramel. The finish is long and intense. It should definitely be eaten alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
