<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whiskies Not Containing Spirit Caramel (E150A) on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bottletags/whiskies-not-containing-spirit-caramel-e150a/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whiskies Not Containing Spirit Caramel (E150A) on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bottletags/whiskies-not-containing-spirit-caramel-e150a/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amrut Peated Cask Strength Indian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/amrut-peated-cask-strength-indian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/amrut-peated-cask-strength-indian/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bowmore Vault Edition First Release Atlantic Sea Salt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bowmore-vault-edition-first-release-atlantic-sea-salt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bowmore-vault-edition-first-release-atlantic-sea-salt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the Bowmore Vault Edition No. 1 Scottish distillery launches a series of four single malt whiskey. With each edition of the four-part series Bowmore deals with one of the typical flavor of Bowmore whiskey. These four basic flavors is part sea salt, smoke, fruit and sweetness. With the first edition Vault Edition 1, Bowmore dedicated the aroma sea salt, so it is a very maritimier single malt in the results, highlighting the origin of the island of Islay unmistakable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coleburn 1972 Rare Old Gordon &amp;amp; MacPhail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/coleburn-1972-rare-old-gordon-macphail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/coleburn-1972-rare-old-gordon-macphail/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jack Daniels Master Distiller No 5 Tennessee Whiskey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jack-daniels-master-distiller-no-5-tennessee-whiskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jack-daniels-master-distiller-no-5-tennessee-whiskey/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glenlivet 1974 /2008 Gordon &amp;amp; MacPhail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/glenlivet-1974-2008-gordon-macphail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/glenlivet-1974-2008-gordon-macphail/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPEY Tenne Cask Strength - Batch 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/spey-tenne-cask-strength-batch-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/spey-tenne-cask-strength-batch-2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glen Grant 1962 /2006 Gordon &amp;amp; MacPhail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/glen-grant-1962-2006-gordon-macphail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/glen-grant-1962-2006-gordon-macphail/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glenglassaugh Port Wood Finish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/glenglassaugh-port-wood-finish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/glenglassaugh-port-wood-finish/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jim Beam Devil&amp;#039;s Cut Bourbon Kentucky Straight Bourbon Whiskey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jim-beam-devils-cut-bourbon-kentucky-straight-bourbon-whiskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jim-beam-devils-cut-bourbon-kentucky-straight-bourbon-whiskey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The counterpart to the &amp;ldquo;Angel&amp;rsquo;s Share&amp;rdquo; (the liquid that &amp;ldquo;evaporated&amp;rdquo; during the Whiskey storage in the drums) is the &amp;ldquo;Devil&amp;rsquo;s Cut&amp;rdquo; (the amount of whiskey, which remains in the timber after the whiskey maturation and emptying of the flamed oak barrels). Thanks to a patented method, which can extract &amp;ldquo;Devil&amp;rsquo;s Cut&amp;rdquo; from the barrels and combine with a minimum of six-year-old Jim Beam. The result is an intense, strong Bourbon, which provides an incomparable taste experience, the Jim Beam Devil&amp;rsquo;s Cut. Jim Beam Bourbon is the best selling brand in the world - Its origins date back to the 18th century, when the German-born Müller Jakob Bohm came with his copper pot stills of Virginia westward to Bourbon Country (Kentucky). It is said to have 1,795 sold his first barrel of whiskey in cash and eventually moved his distillery to Washington County. Jim (James Beauregard) Beam was Jacob Boehm&amp;rsquo;s great-grandson. It joined the family business at the age of 16 years. The Jim Beam Devils Cut whiskey is produced in Clermont, in the US state of Kentucky. The well-known distillery has been producing since 1795. whiskey. The Jim Beam Devils Cut is a new creation. When storing two &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; Outtakes &amp;lsquo;distinguish&amp;rsquo;. The &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; angel&amp;rsquo;s cut &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; is the portion that evaporates during maturation by the barrel pores, the &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; devil&amp;rsquo;s cut &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; is the residue that remains after emptying of the barrels. This relatively small amount, the &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; Devil&amp;rsquo;s share &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, is married with six year old Jim Beam whiskey and produces a particularly rich, intense whiskey with an equally strong coloration. The bouquet is smoky oak flavors and delicate vanilla unfold. On the palate, the new creation convinces with an intense vanilla and cinnamon note, wood and caramel. The finish is long and intense. It should definitely be eaten alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bruichladdich Black Art 6.1 1990 26 Year Old</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bruichladdich-black-art-6-1-1990-26-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bruichladdich-black-art-6-1-1990-26-year-old/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roughstock Montana Pure Malt Whiskey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/roughstock-montana-pure-malt-whiskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/roughstock-montana-pure-malt-whiskey/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benriach 21 Year Old Tawny Port Finish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/benriach-21-year-old-tawny-port-finish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/benriach-21-year-old-tawny-port-finish/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Peat Islay Blended Malt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/big-peat-islay-blended-malt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/big-peat-islay-blended-malt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Big Peat convinces with its strong smoky and phenolic character that will convince especially lovers of Islay whiskeys. According to the manufacturer of the Big Peat should represent the ultimate taste of Islay. A Hidden Malt, which reflects the taste of Islay - the Big Peat. known in normal filling, but now available in a miniature, it is referred to by experts as the ultimate Islay whiskey. Five distilleries are in the process involved in creating this unique blend. Four of them deliver their varieties Port Ellen, Ardbeg, Bowmore and coal Ila. The fifth part in the processing and fills from. The result is a joint project of the islanders, which now is very popular among friends of the original and peaty whiskeys. Both smell and taste live mainly of smoke and peat, but replaced by a discreet sweetness. In addition, the connoisseurs will recognize the aroma of beach and tar, smoke and peat. The finish of the taste of liquorice and fire support the main flavor. Friends speak of understated nut character, baked almonds and salted cashews to which this whiskey recalls. In addition, a touch of cocoa beans and sandalwood - It is also quite dry. A coveted award was the Big Peat given in 13: It was winner of the title &amp;ldquo;Best Blended Scotch Malt Whiskey&amp;rdquo; at the World Awards. This maybe also contributed to the unusual label, reminiscent of a comic book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glenfarclas 15 Year Old 70cl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/glenfarclas-15-year-old-70cl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 18:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/glenfarclas-15-year-old-70cl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Glenfarclas 15 Years is an outstanding Scottish single malt whiskey. It particularly shines through the excellent combination of sherry and barley. 95/100 pts. Jim Murray&amp;rsquo;s Whiskey Bible 2010 Glenfarclas is one of the largest distilleries in Scotland. Robert Hay founded the distillery in 1836 and since 1844 quality whiskeys are produced there. At this point, Hay also received the official license to be allowed to burn whiskeys. 1865, the distillery changed hands and went into the hands of John Grant. To date, it is owned by the Grant family. All whiskey from Glenfarclas mature exclusively been used sherry casks. The Glenfarclas 15 years Speyside Malt Scotch Whiskey had 15 years for his maturation. Thus, this is an excellent whiskey that can go into raptures even connoisseurs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
