<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Islay Whiskies on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bottletags/islay-whiskies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Islay Whiskies on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bottletags/islay-whiskies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ardbeg Uigeadail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ardbeg-uigeadail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ardbeg-uigeadail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ardbeg Uigeadail combines the typical Ardbeg flavors, smokiness and salty notes, with chocolaty sweetness and raisin flavors. fit Montecristo cigars to this whiskey. Named after the Uigeadail source from which the Ardbeg distillery produces its peaty water, the Ardbeg Uigeadail sets new standards in matters of complexity and harmony. The 10-year marriage bourbon barrels with older sherry casks gives an abundance of flavors, which in addition magnificently describe the Ardbeg Uigeadail. The connection Islay &amp;amp; Ardbeg typical aromas with flavors of sherry casks is unique. The Ardbeg Islay Uigeadail is a single malt whiskey, which is produced in the region of Scotland Islay. the clear waters of Ardbeg, which gives a pleasant peaty taste the whiskey is used. The maturation takes place in bourbon and sherry casks, which is noticeable in the aroma. This looks smoky, intense smells of leather, tobacco and a slight fruitiness. Also on the palate also one perceives smokiness, a light malt flavor, licorice and a hint of citrus. Overall, a balanced, lush taste. In conclusion, the connoisseurs of a long-lasting taste pleased paired with a fine sherry. An aromatic wine for connoisseurs and novices alike. The Ardbeg Islay Whiskey Uigeadail should be in every bar. The best It tasted straight or with some ice. Ardbeg Uigeadail is a 70 year old single malt whisky from the Ardbeg whisky distillery (located in the Islay region). Rated an average of 4.6 out of 5 by 797 reviewers and available from Master of Malt for only £52.95, falling slightly short of liquid gold but this in a solid everyday single malt whisky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laphroaig 27 Year Old /2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/laphroaig-27-year-old-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/laphroaig-27-year-old-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Port Ellen 1979 23 Year Old Sherry Cask /Wilson &amp;amp; Morgan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/port-ellen-1979-23-year-old-sherry-cask-wilson-morgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/port-ellen-1979-23-year-old-sherry-cask-wilson-morgan/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bowmore Vault Edition First Release Atlantic Sea Salt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bowmore-vault-edition-first-release-atlantic-sea-salt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bowmore-vault-edition-first-release-atlantic-sea-salt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the Bowmore Vault Edition No. 1 Scottish distillery launches a series of four single malt whiskey. With each edition of the four-part series Bowmore deals with one of the typical flavor of Bowmore whiskey. These four basic flavors is part sea salt, smoke, fruit and sweetness. With the first edition Vault Edition 1, Bowmore dedicated the aroma sea salt, so it is a very maritimier single malt in the results, highlighting the origin of the island of Islay unmistakable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bruichladdich Black Art 6.1 1990 26 Year Old</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bruichladdich-black-art-6-1-1990-26-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bruichladdich-black-art-6-1-1990-26-year-old/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lagavulin 16 Year Old 70cl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lagavulin-16-year-old-70cl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lagavulin-16-year-old-70cl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Lagavulin 16 Years is the best-selling member of the Classic Malts of Scotland. A powerful, smoky and complex Islay Malt. A true classic! The distillery Lagavulin on Islay is renowned for its peaty whiskeys. It is located in close proximity to the distilleries of Ardbeg and Laphroaig. This also applies to the Lagavulin 16 Years. Although the finish and sherry casks (Sherry Cask) were used remains that there are strong, smoky. Beginners should not start with this whiskey. The Lagavulin 16 Years is a whiskey for connoisseurs and lovers of Islay whiskeys. The Lavagulin 16 Years Old Islay Malt is said to have an absolutely unmistakable and strong character. It has an unrivaled composition of earth, sea, peat and smoke. When speaking of the spiciest Islay Malt, as connoisseurs know that here the Lavagulin 16 Years Old is meant. Especially popular is the 43% vol. alcoholic Lavagulin due to its deep taste and its noble drought. The 16-year-old whiskey is the most popular and best selling Classic Malt series. The flavor notes of Lavagulin 16 Years Old Islay Malt consist of fruity cherry, delicate vanilla and other various spices. More information about the product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Peat Islay Blended Malt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/big-peat-islay-blended-malt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/big-peat-islay-blended-malt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Big Peat convinces with its strong smoky and phenolic character that will convince especially lovers of Islay whiskeys. According to the manufacturer of the Big Peat should represent the ultimate taste of Islay. A Hidden Malt, which reflects the taste of Islay - the Big Peat. known in normal filling, but now available in a miniature, it is referred to by experts as the ultimate Islay whiskey. Five distilleries are in the process involved in creating this unique blend. Four of them deliver their varieties Port Ellen, Ardbeg, Bowmore and coal Ila. The fifth part in the processing and fills from. The result is a joint project of the islanders, which now is very popular among friends of the original and peaty whiskeys. Both smell and taste live mainly of smoke and peat, but replaced by a discreet sweetness. In addition, the connoisseurs will recognize the aroma of beach and tar, smoke and peat. The finish of the taste of liquorice and fire support the main flavor. Friends speak of understated nut character, baked almonds and salted cashews to which this whiskey recalls. In addition, a touch of cocoa beans and sandalwood - It is also quite dry. A coveted award was the Big Peat given in 13: It was winner of the title &amp;ldquo;Best Blended Scotch Malt Whiskey&amp;rdquo; at the World Awards. This maybe also contributed to the unusual label, reminiscent of a comic book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lagavulin 12 Year Old /1980s</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lagavulin-12-year-old-1980s/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lagavulin-12-year-old-1980s/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bunnahabhain 1997 20 Year Old Acorn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bunnahabhain-1997-20-year-old-acorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bunnahabhain-1997-20-year-old-acorn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
