<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Staples on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bottletags/staples/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Staples on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bottletags/staples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ardbeg Uigeadail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ardbeg-uigeadail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ardbeg-uigeadail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ardbeg Uigeadail combines the typical Ardbeg flavors, smokiness and salty notes, with chocolaty sweetness and raisin flavors. fit Montecristo cigars to this whiskey. Named after the Uigeadail source from which the Ardbeg distillery produces its peaty water, the Ardbeg Uigeadail sets new standards in matters of complexity and harmony. The 10-year marriage bourbon barrels with older sherry casks gives an abundance of flavors, which in addition magnificently describe the Ardbeg Uigeadail. The connection Islay &amp;amp; Ardbeg typical aromas with flavors of sherry casks is unique. The Ardbeg Islay Uigeadail is a single malt whiskey, which is produced in the region of Scotland Islay. the clear waters of Ardbeg, which gives a pleasant peaty taste the whiskey is used. The maturation takes place in bourbon and sherry casks, which is noticeable in the aroma. This looks smoky, intense smells of leather, tobacco and a slight fruitiness. Also on the palate also one perceives smokiness, a light malt flavor, licorice and a hint of citrus. Overall, a balanced, lush taste. In conclusion, the connoisseurs of a long-lasting taste pleased paired with a fine sherry. An aromatic wine for connoisseurs and novices alike. The Ardbeg Islay Whiskey Uigeadail should be in every bar. The best It tasted straight or with some ice. Ardbeg Uigeadail is a 70 year old single malt whisky from the Ardbeg whisky distillery (located in the Islay region). Rated an average of 4.6 out of 5 by 797 reviewers and available from Master of Malt for only £52.95, falling slightly short of liquid gold but this in a solid everyday single malt whisky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talisker 10 Year Old</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/talisker-10-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/talisker-10-year-old/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Talisker 10 Years is strong in flavor, peppery and marked by maritime flavors. The Talisker 10 Years is delivered in a gift box! The Talisker 10 comes from the single distillery of the Isle of Skye. The whiskeys of the distillery are among the most popular spirits in the world. To date, one of the pfeffrigsten Single Malts is baked in the world in the distillery. Smoky, malty-sweet, with very strong pepper. For several years It has been a fixed feature of the Classic Malts Selection. This has made it even more popular, despite or because of the very strong flavors. At least once you should have the Talisker 10 Years tried. Talisker 10 Years is a 10 year old Scottish single malt Scotch whiskey. It is produced by the Talisker Distillery, the only distillery on the Isle of Skye in Scotland. The Talisker 10 Years tastes sweet dried fruit, but also has a smoky and peppery note. Especially in the finish It is very strong, here are the peppery comes into its own. Its aroma is also characterized by strong peat smoke, which is in contrast to the fruity sweetness and so shapes the unique taste of Talisker whiskey, making it thus one of the most powerful in taste malts, which are currently producing. Clearly visible is the Talisker 10 Years on his golden brown, rich color.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lagavulin 16 Year Old 70cl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lagavulin-16-year-old-70cl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lagavulin-16-year-old-70cl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Lagavulin 16 Years is the best-selling member of the Classic Malts of Scotland. A powerful, smoky and complex Islay Malt. A true classic! The distillery Lagavulin on Islay is renowned for its peaty whiskeys. It is located in close proximity to the distilleries of Ardbeg and Laphroaig. This also applies to the Lagavulin 16 Years. Although the finish and sherry casks (Sherry Cask) were used remains that there are strong, smoky. Beginners should not start with this whiskey. The Lagavulin 16 Years is a whiskey for connoisseurs and lovers of Islay whiskeys. The Lavagulin 16 Years Old Islay Malt is said to have an absolutely unmistakable and strong character. It has an unrivaled composition of earth, sea, peat and smoke. When speaking of the spiciest Islay Malt, as connoisseurs know that here the Lavagulin 16 Years Old is meant. Especially popular is the 43% vol. alcoholic Lavagulin due to its deep taste and its noble drought. The 16-year-old whiskey is the most popular and best selling Classic Malt series. The flavor notes of Lavagulin 16 Years Old Islay Malt consist of fruity cherry, delicate vanilla and other various spices. More information about the product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redbreast 12 Year Old Single Pot Still Irish Whiskey 70cl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/redbreast-12-year-old-single-pot-still-irish-whiskey-70cl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 13:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/redbreast-12-year-old-single-pot-still-irish-whiskey-70cl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among connoisseurs of Redbreast 12 Years among the best what of whiskies to offer Ireland. The phases of maturity in bourbon and Oloroso cask give the Redbreast 12 Years unbeatable and rare taste. 1939 Redbreast is the first time in the trade. it was produced at that time in the Jameson distillery, stored, packaged and sold it the company has Gilbey. After the Jameson distillery was closed, one has the pure pot still delivered only to mid 80s. A few years ago the brand was revived thanks to the IDG and manufactured in New Midleton today. Earlier the Redbreast had an excellent reputation and is considered one of the last Irish whiskey of its kind. The Redbreast 12 Years is a world class pure pot still whiskey. The bottle is also called &amp;ldquo;The Priest Bottle&amp;rdquo; because the Irish pot still to have earlier pampers the palate of priests. The Redbreast is a traditional Irish whiskey, which is produced in the pot still procedure. This means that the distillation is carried out in stills of copper. Because after each operation, the bubbles must be cleaned carefully, the Redbreast is not suitable for mass production. Furthermore, the addition of water is omitted before bottling. The concentration is the same as that in the storage barrels. Of course, the alcohol content of the whiskey is high and only for hard-drinking connoisseurs. The aroma of Redbreast is fruity with hints of malt and sherry. The latter comes from the storage casks. The taste is very diverse, with hints of sherry, spices, vanilla and oak. A total of more powerful and complex taste. The finish also not disappointed: very long lasting, intense with hints of dark berry fruits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
