<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whisky-News on Uisge Beatha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/whisky-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whisky-News on Uisge Beatha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:35:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/whisky-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is The Angels Share?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-is-the-angels-share/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:35:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-is-the-angels-share/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://uisgebeatha.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/the-angels-share.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;What Is The Angels Share? 1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Angels Share is alcohol lost due to evaporation during the maturation of whisky. The exact amount lost to evaporation varies based on the properties of the wood, the skill of the cooper, the humidity of the region and how regularly the casks are turned. The term is also the name of a Scottish comedy drama directed by Ken Loach centered around a fictional cask of Islay’s Malt Mill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distilling The myth of Canadian Whisky</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/distilling-myth-canadian-whisky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 12:47:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/distilling-myth-canadian-whisky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Canadian whisky sometimes suffers from a whirlwind of contrary media, some going so far as to call it brown vodka, some calling it the best whisky in the world and others highlighting the 9.09% rule.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Still Vs. Pot Still</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/continuous-still-vs-pot-still/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 21:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/continuous-still-vs-pot-still/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The difference of flavour between Malt and Blend whiskies can &lt;em&gt;largely&lt;/em&gt; be traced to three factors, the grain used, the way it&amp;rsquo;s distilled, and the way the alcohol is matured. While the influence of the later is cited as high as 70%&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glenmorangie Unseen Pop-Up London</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/glenmorangie-unseen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 10:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/glenmorangie-unseen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those Scots lucky enough to find themselves in London, or whisky drinkers this end of the country Glenmorangie have announced their first ever pop-up event in the heart of Soho. Running from the 13th to the 21st of March (excluding the 15th) to promote the brands new quarterly digital publication the pop-up will feature unseen cocktails crafted by expert mixologists, as well as food pairings and the &amp;ldquo;Glenmorangie vault&amp;rdquo; featuring the Glenmorangie 1963, the 1970&amp;rsquo;s collection and the Glenmorangie Pride 1978 so put this one in your diary now!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Zealand 25 Year Old 1988 is Liquid Gold</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/new-zealand-25-year-old-1988-liquid-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 08:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/new-zealand-25-year-old-1988-liquid-gold/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://uiscebeatha.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/operations_manager_grant_finn-1-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;operations_manager_grant_finn&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jim Murray author of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://uiscebeatha.co.uk/whisky-2015/&#34;&gt;whisky bible&lt;/a&gt; has been exploring the southern hemispheres whisky offering and by all accounts is considerably impressed. The 1988 New Zealand Whisky Collection (25 years) has just been awarded 96.5 (out of 100) and the status of liquid gold. Produced in the now closed Willowbank distillery and bought by the New Zealand Whisky Collection this whisky will be the last of it&amp;rsquo;s line and the circa £130 price tag is likely to push on up so grab yourself a bottle while you can.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The £1 million Rose of Annandale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/annandale-distillery-first-cask/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 19:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/annandale-distillery-first-cask/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Annandale distillery re-opened in 2007 has become the first Scotch to put its first cask up for sale, for the eye-watering price of £1 million. In a stroke of marketing genius that will certainly make the world take notice. The restored and refurbished whisky distillery and visitor centre sees the water of life return to Dumfries-shire a long term dream of Professor David Thompson 59 his wife Teresa Church 55. Production began in 2014 and the first fill is expected to be matured for at least 10 years, though it could legally be opened in 2018 after maturing for its &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uiscebeatha.co.uk/bourbon-vs-whisky/&#34;&gt;minimum of 3 years&lt;/a&gt; and still be considered a Scotch&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Heads, One Ambition &amp; A New Website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hankey-bannister-webiste/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 23:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hankey-bannister-webiste/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In addition to being a whisky enthusiast I&amp;rsquo;m also a digital marketer, and I&amp;rsquo;ve previously written about my whisky personal pet peeves - which you can find in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://uiscebeatha.co.uk/whisky-digital-marketing/&#34; title=&#34;Whisky and Digital Marketing&#34;&gt;marketing article.&lt;/a&gt; Every now and again though you come across a site which does it well, reminding you that some brands are embracing digital.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barley &amp; The James Hutton Institute</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/barley-james-hutton-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 08:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/barley-james-hutton-institute/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from the publishing of a high resolution draft of the barley genome in the journal Nature the James Hutton Institute is hoping to establish a £23m international centre for the study of barley, with the hopes of creating hardier, more resistant strains for use the production of biofuel, beer and of course whisky. Barley is already the second most important crop in UK agriculture, grown across almost 50% of Scotland&amp;rsquo;s arable land and underpinning the Scotch whisky industry &lt;a href=&#34;http://uiscebeatha.co.uk/scotch-whisky-industry-turmoil/&#34;&gt;£5 billion&lt;/a&gt; per year contribution to the UK economy, so this development is likely to receive considerable support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glenlivet 12 to be Discontinued?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/glenlivet-12-discontinued/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 23:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/glenlivet-12-discontinued/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Disturbing rumours are surfacing regarding the future of the Glenlivet 12 in key markets, although as yet not clear reports from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whisky.de/shop/Schottland/Single-Malt/Highland-G/Glenlivet-12-Jahre--.html&#34;&gt;Whisky.de&lt;/a&gt; suggest that this flagship is to be replaced by the newly launched Founder’s Reserve in some countries, in others these are likely to be sold side by side.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
